Purendra Agrawal

https://www.linkedin.com/in/purendraagrawal/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

An IT professional having 4 years of experience in software testing. Exploring better opportunities to utilize and enhance my **technical knowledge**, **strategic** and **problem-solving** skills to set new benchmarks. My aim is to work in challenging environment where I can utilize my expertise in resolving the problem in test plan.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology(Hons.) in Information Technology from Krishna institute of Technology, Kanpur affiliated to Gautama Buddha technical university, Lucknow with 76% in 2014.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Languages: Core JAVA, SQL, VBScript, HTML
- **Testing skills:** Selenium, HP UFT(QTP), HP ALM (Quality center), Regression testing, Automation testing, Manual testing, Test planning, TestNG, Log4J, Git, Jenkins, Microsoft VSTS

WORK EXPERIENCE

SSP Worldwide

Test Engineer

Gurgaon, India April 2018 - Present

Email: Purendra.agrawal@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-8899406155

Roles & key activities:

- Current role involves creating and maintaining the automation framework.
- Following the Agile methodology and using the tool Microsoft VSTS (AZURE) and TFS.
- Using Gitlab as a code repository and Git for version control.
- Following the DevOps approach after creating the automation test suite.
- Working in different teams as an automation tester in a company.

Infosys Limited

Test Engineer

Chandigarh, India February 2015 – April 2018

Client:

Morgan Stanley

Client have set of applications used by many corporate users. These applications include Corp creation, client creation, Participant creation in the client, Issue grants, awards and Shares for participant, exercises, releases and access control to users.

Roles & key activities:

- Role involves writing, execution and maintenance of test scripts/cases using Selenium and UFT/QTP tool.
- Developed the data driven testing framework from scratch in Selenium using programming language Java and the design pattern is Page Object Model.
- Used Bitbucket as a code repository and Git for version control.
- Understanding the application flow to investigate any issues that violates the trade flow.
- Exposure to all stages of test automation life cycle such as Feasibility analysis, automation framework creation, scripting, debugging, test execution and test results analysis & reporting.
- Participated in identifying the high-level scenarios and creating the test cases.
- Support the creation of functional requirement documents by creating specifications based on client inputs and preparing the test design documents.
- Understanding business requirements and clarify doubts from business analyst if required.
- Reporting Status and taking Status call with client on release progress.
- Participate in onsite-offshore interactions as required, prepare and submit daily status reports to supervisor and provide timely updates for project trackers.
- Worked closely with the developers leading to the successful releases.

Infosys Limited

System engineer trainee

Mysore, India October 2014 – January 2015

Completed several trainings as a trainee:

- Object oriented programming skills
- Software Engineering and Web Technology
- Database management System
- Automation testing using UFT tool

ACHIEVEMENT AND EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Participated in Zero distance plan and got appreciation from client and Infosys for automation to save time and money around 50k dollar per year in manual processing of test data setup.
- Got appreciation from Infosys for working on multiple projects with strict deadlines.
- Working as a Freelancer in Testing and completed the testing of BHIM app and got rewarded.
- Was awarded the 1st prize in AAROHAN on screen technical ppt. presentation.
- Was awarded the 1st prize in Counter Strike event.

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

- Volunteer of Infosys CSR: ARPAN
- Head coordinator of Marketing team in Inception 2013 and Annihilation 2013.
- Event coordinator of Gamers Arena 2013
- Overall Coordinator of ANVESHAN 2012